Guide to the A. B. Cook Papers 1882-1940
Montana Historical Society Archives
- A.B. Cook Stock Farms
  - Subject Files
    - Irrigation: Louis K. Pool re Lower Reed Ditch, 1919 (Box-folder 38 / 16)
    - Keyes, VanVechten and Kennedy leases (includes correspondence, application, tax assessment), 1925-1927 (Box-folder 38 / 17)
    - Latin America (includes letters from cattlemen in Latin America), 1920-1921 (Box-folder 38 / 18)
    - Livestock Sanitary Board inspections, 1920, 1926 (Box-folder 38 / 19)
    - Livestock Loan Company (proposed), 1925 (Box-folder 38 / 20)
    - Loan application to Montana Joint Stock Land Bank of Helena on Sheep Creek Ranch (includes correspondence, inventory, etc.), 1922 (Box-folder 38 / 21)
    - Loan companies (includes John Clay and Company, Montana Livestock Finance Company, Tri-City Land Company; see also correspondence file for each company), 1921-1927 (Box-folder 38 / 22)
    - Luppold Ranch lease from Emelia McStravick (includes correspondence, lease papers, etc.), 1922, 1926 (Box-folder 38 / 23)
    - Frank Miracle land, 1920, 1926 (Box-folder 38 / 24)
    - Montana Potato Improvement Association (includes report of 4th annual meeting), 1927 (Box-folder 38 / 25)
    - Montana State Poultry Association, ROM Turkey Breeders Division, 1929 (Box-folder 39 / 1)
    - Morgan's mining equipment, 1928? (Box-folder 39 / 2)
    - National Forest grazing leases [map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1918-1924 (Box-folder 39 / 3)
    - New Zealand and Australian Land Company, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 39 / 4)
    - Newlan Creek Ranch (Harry H. Keyes), 1923-1928 (Box-folder 39 / 5)
    - Pictures (re orders for prints, photographs, frames), 1916-1918 (Box-folder 39 / 6)
    - Plans and drawings for buildings and equipment [see also map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1917-1926 (Box-folder 39 / 7)
    - Railroad rates, 1922-1926 (Box-folder 39 / 8)
    - Ranch lands (includes some ranches offered for sale) [map in OVERSIZE FOLDER 5], 1917-1926 (Box-folder 39 / 9)
    - Roses, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 39 / 10)
    - Seeding, 1926 (Box-folder 39 / 11)
    - Sheep, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 39 / 12)
    - Sheep Creek Ranch (bought from Thomas A. Marlow), 1916-1923 (Box-folder 39 / 13)
    - Show herd (re expenses, prizes, pedigrees at fairs; see also "Fairs, expositions and sales"), 1926-1927 (Box-folder 39 / 14)
    - Silos (re building of brick silos on ranch), 1918-1920 (Box-folder 39 / 15)
    - Sioux City sale of A.B. Cook Herefords, 1920 (Box-folder 39 / 16)
    - State leases, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 39 / 17)
    - Twin Cities Land Company (re Ballard and Company mortgage), 1923-1926 (Box-folder 39 / 18)
    - Veterinary medical remedies, etc., 1922-1927 (Box-folder 39 / 19)
    - Water rights on Confederate Creek, 1890-1928 (Box-folder 39 / 20)
  - Miscellany
    - American Hereford Cattle Breeders Association financial report, 1917 (Box-folder 39 / 21)
    - American National Live Stock Association programs, reports, ICC docket, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 39 / 22)
    - Automobile titles and registration, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 39 / 23)
    - Cattle breeders lists, 1923, n.d. (Box-folder 39 / 24)
    - Fair brochures, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 39 / 25)
    - Graham Scientific Breeding School brochures, n.d. (Box-folder 39 / 26)
    - Hereford cattle record keeping methods, 1920 (Box-folder 39 / 27)
    - Indexes (unidentified) (Box-folder 40 / 1-2)
    - Lists of land holdings, 1924, n.d. (Box-folder 40 / 3)
    - Petition for federal aid highway over Duck Creek Pass, 1927 (Box-folder 40 / 4)
    - T.C. Power Company price lists, 1921-1927 (Box-folder 40 / 5)
    - Soil analyses, 1920 (Box-folder 40 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous (includes brochures, advertisements, catalogs, etc.), 1921-1928 (Box-folder 40 / 7)
  - Clippings
    - A.B. Cook, his show herd, and dispersal sale, 1921-1928 (Box-folder 40 / 8)
    - Resorts and dude ranches, 1925 (Box-folder 40 / 9)
    - Weeds, soils, livestock, etc., 1921-1928 (Box-folder 40 / 10)
- Flying U Ranch (Bynum, Mont.)
  - General Correspondence
    - B-C (correspondents include A.W. Beach; George A. Chichester; Clay, Robinson and Company; Frank Conley; Conrad Banking Company; Conrad-Stanford Company; Creeklyn Stock Farm; Thomas A. Cummings), 1908-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 11)
    - J.L. DeHart, 1907-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 12)
    - G-M (correspondents include Great Falls Meat Company, Hirshberg Mercantile Company, Montana State Land Dept.), 1908-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 13)
    - Rosenbaum Brothers and Company, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 14)
    - George Sim, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 40 / 15)
    - Axel Swanson, 1908-1911 (Box-folder 40 / 16)
    - Truman's Pioneer Stud Farm, 1907-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 17)
    - Carlos Warfield, 1906-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 18)
  - Employment Records
    - Employee accounts, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 40 / 19)
  - Financial Records
    - Bills, receipts, etc., 1908-1912 (Box-folder 40 / 20)
    - Cattle purchases, 1908 (Box-folder 40 / 21)
    - Cattle sales, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 40 / 22)
    - Check register, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 40 / 23)
    - Horse transfers, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 40 / 24)
    - Inventories, n.d. (Box-folder 40 / 25)
    - Taxes: Teton County, 1908-1917 (Box-folder 40 / 26)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstract of title, homestead certificate, deeds, bills of sale, lease, 1892-1912 (Box-folder 40 / 27)
- Stiles Cattle Company (Standing Rock Reservation, S.d.)
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include J.A. Stiles, L. Earl, J.W. Schock, Jack Ramey; includes report of Perry P. Kline), 1917-1928 (Box-folder 41 / 1-4)
    - Telegrams, 1917-1926 (Box-folder 41 / 5-6)
  - General Correspondence
    - A. McG. Beede, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 41 / 7)
    - John Clay and Company, 1925 (Box-folder 41 / 8)
    - H.C. Smith, 1925 (Box-folder 41 / 9)
    - Ed Straub (Standing Rock Reservation, S.D.), 1918 (Box-folder 41 / 10)
    - U.S. Indian Service: Standing Rock Indian School (E.D. Mossman), 1923-1925 (Box-folder 41 / 11)
    - A-W (correspondents include Capital Live Stock Loan Company, Chappel Brothers, Joseph A. Hanlon, Live Stock National Bank, O'Neil Brothers, Bud O'Neil, Oscar L. Payne, Sioux County, Western South Dakota Stock Growers Association), 1922-1928 (Box-folder 41 / 12)
  - Financial Records
    - Delinquent taxes, 1925 (Box-folder 41 / 13)
    - Financial statements, 1918-1926 (Box-folder 41 / 14)
    - Property sold at auction, 1924 (Box-folder 41 / 15)
    - Schedule of damages assessed for trespass on Indian lands, 1923, 1925 (Box-folder 41 / 16)
    - Miscellaneous (includes cancelled checks, bills, memo books, taxes), 1923-1925 (Box-folder 41 / 17)
  - Maps
    - Maps of Stiles Cattle Company and Standing Rock Indian Reservation, including property ownership on reservation, 1909. 1911, n.d. (Box-folder OvFd / 6)
  - Production Records
    - Cattle lists, tatoo numbers. etc., n.d. (Box-folder 41 / 18-19)
    - Cattle registrations and transfers (mostly to A.B. Cook), 1918-1923 (Box-folder 41 / 20)
  - Miscellany
    - Lists of lands leased on Standing Rock Reservation (gives names of Indian land owners), 1922-1924 (Box-folder 41 / 21)
    - Lists of lands purchased on Standing Rock Reservation (gives names of sellers), 1920 (Box-folder 41 / 22)
- A.b. Cook (Bynum Reservoir Contract)
  - General Correspondence
    - Re court case (correspondents include S.J. Mayo, U.S. General Land Office, John G. Brown, John W. Alvord, Jeremiah Collins, Milton S. Gunn, Albert J. Galen), 1912-1915 (Box-folder 42 / 1)
  - Court Papers
    - A.K. Prescott et al. vs. Teton Cooperative Reservoir Company and A.B. Cook, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 42 / 2-3)
  - Employment Records
    - Payroll and timebook, 1908-1909 (Volume Vol. 2)
  - Financial Records
    - Account with A.B. Cook and Company re Belt work, 1909-1912 (Box-folder 42 / 4)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: A-B, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 5)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: J.I. Case Threshing Machine Company, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 6)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: Conrad Mercantile Company, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 7)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: Cook, Deeks, Hinds and Company, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 8)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: C-G, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 9-10)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: Hirshberg Mercantile Company, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 11)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: H-L, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 12)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: Murphy-Maclay Hardware Company, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 13)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: M-R, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 14)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: Western Wheeled Scraper Company, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 15)
    - Bills, receipts, orders, etc.: Winston, Harper, Fisher Company, wholesale groceries, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 16)
    - Inventory, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 17)
    - Ledger, 1908 (Box-folder 42 / 18)
    - Trial balances, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 42 / 19)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreements with Cal Binford and B.P. Derkson to supply oats, 1909 (Box-folder 42 / 20)
- Banner Mining Company
  - Financial Records
    - Taxes: Lewis and Clark County, 1899-1921 (Box-folder 42 / 21)
  - Legal Documents
    - Sale of Banner claim to Cook by G.F. Woodruff and Annie Hollen, 1894 (Box-folder 42 / 22)
  - Organization
    - Stock certificate, 1895 (Box-folder 42 / 23)
- Buckeye Mining And Milling Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include O.B. Hanley, T.H. Burke, A.J. Steele), 1890-1891 (Box-folder 42 / 24)
  - Assay Reports
    - Assay certificates, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 42 / 25)
  - Employment Records
    - Payroll / timebook, 1891 (Box-folder 42 / 26)
  - Financial Records
    - Checkstubs, 1892 (Box-folder 42 / 27)
    - Miscellaneous (includes statement of ore sales, trial balances, loan payments, bill, inventory of tools), 1890-1894, n.d. (Box-folder 42 / 28)
  - Legal Documents
    - Notice of location and declaratory statement for Ohio mill site, 1890 (Box-folder 42 / 29)
  - Organization
    - Stock certificates, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 42 / 30)
  - Reports
    - Report on Ohio Climax and Paymaster mines, 1889 (Box-folder 42 / 31)
- Cook And Woldson, Railroad Contractors
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Richard A. Harlow, Montana Railroad Company, Smith Brothers Sheep Company), 1895, 1900 (Box-folder 43 / 1)
  - Employments Records
    - Payroll checkstubs, timebooks, etc., 1893, 1895 (Box-folder 43 / 2-3)
  - Financial Records
    - Bank statements, 1897-1901 (Box-folder 43 / 4)
    - Bills, invoices, receipts, etc.: Whitehall spur to Parrot smelter, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 43 / 5-7)
    - Cancelled checks and checkstubs, 1895-1900 (Box-folder 43 / 8-12)
    - Cancelled checks and checkstubs, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 44 / 1)
    - Daybook, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 44 / 2)
    - Hauling Cumberland ore, 1896-1897 (Box-folder 44 / 3)
    - Journal: Gaylord and Ruby Valley Railway; Gallatin Railroad; tie hauling, 1897-1899 (Box-folder 44 / 4)
    - Journals: Montana Railroad force account, 1899-1900 (Volume Vol. 3-4)
    - Journal: Montana Railroad force account and cash book, 1900 (Box-folder 44 / 5)
    - Journal: Montana Railroad grading account; Dorsey subcontract; Martinsdale to Marino extension, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 44 / 6)
    - Journal: Whitehall spur to Parrot Smelter, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 44 / 7)
    - Ledger, 1897-1899 (Box-folder 44 / 8)
    - Ledgers, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 45 / 1-3)
    - Montana Railroad accounts, 1896-1900 (Box-folder 45 / 4-5)
    - Montana Railroad force of work report, 1899 (Box-folder 45 / 6)
    - Taxes: Lewis and Clark County, 1900 (Box-folder 45 / 7)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts (includes Northern Pacific Railway Company for spur line from Whitehall to Parrot smelter; Butte, Anaconda and Pacific Railway Company; Richard A. Harlow for line to Castle Mining District; Gaylord and Ruby Valley Railway Company; Dorsey Company for subcontract laying track from Summit Station to Martinsdale for Montana Railroad Company), 1895-1899 (Box-folder 45 / 8)
  - Miscellany
    - Advertisement for bids for work in Yellowstone National Park, 1902 (Box-folder 45 / 9)
    - Railroad construction specifications and cost estimates, 1888-1913, n.d. (Box-folder 45 / 10)
- Cook Construction Company
  - General Correspondence
    - A-B (correspondents include A.R. Armstrong, Bank of Toronto, Burlington Steel Company), 1913-1918 (Box-folder 46 / 1)
    - Canadian Government Railways, Halifax Ocean Terminals, 1919 (Box-folder 46 / 2)
    - Canadian Pacific Railway Company, 1905-1925 (Box-folder 46 / 3)
    - A.H. Cederberg, 1917 (Box-folder 46 / 4)
    - Cook Construction Company, St. Paul, Minn. (correspondents include J.F. Higgins, Alexander McKenzie, H.B. Shoop), 1912-1921 (Box-folder 46 / 5-8)
    - Cook Construction Company, Ltd., Montreal, Que. (correspondents include F.J. Herlihy, F.I. Ker, Harry F. McLean, Alexander McKenzie), 1912-1922, 1928 (Box-folder 46 / 9-12)
    - Cook Construction Company, Ltd. and Wheaton Brothers, Halifax, N.S. (correspondents include Harry F. McLean, J.P. Bains), 1916-1918 (Box-folder 46 / 13)
    - Cook Construction Company (telegrams, all three locations), 1912-1922 (Box-folder 46 / 14-15)
    - C (correspondents include Canada Cement Company Ltd., Canadian Northern Railway, Canadian Vickers Ltd., Canadian government agencies, J.D. Cumming), 1914-1920 (Box-folder 46 / 16)
    - Dominion Construction Company, 1918 (Box-folder 47 / 1)
    - D-H (correspondents include Maurice E. Davis; Paul Faber; George P. Flannery; C.B. Foster; Gaffy, Stephens and McNamee; Halifax Board of Trade; Henry Holgate; Hoosier Rolling Mill Company), 1915-1923 (Box-folder 47 / 2)
    - MacDonell and Boland (correspondents include A.G. MacDonell, W.J. Boland), 1910-1915 (Box-folder 47 / 3)
    - M-N (correspondents include Boyd Magee, Miami Conservancy District, Wallace Nesbitt), 1917-1921 (Box-folder 47 / 4)
    - W.H. Rosecrans Engineering Company, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 47 / 5)
    - S (correspondents include L.I. Stephens, A.M. Stewart), 1917-1920 (Box-folder 47 / 6)
    - Carlos Warfield, 1914 (Box-folder 47 / 7)
  - Court Papers
    - Thomas Burke vs. Cook and Hinds Railroad Contractors, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 47 / 8)
    - In the matter of a seizure by the Commissioner of Customs of plant and machinery, property of Cook Construction Company, Ltd., 1914 (Box-folder 47 / 9)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book / voucher register, 1913-1916 (Volume Vol. 5)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway distribution of yardage and progress estimates, 1914 (Box-folder 47 / 10)
    - Estimate of profits on construction of Montreal, Joliette, and Transcontinental Junction Railway, ca. 1914 (Box-folder 47 / 11)
    - Inventories, 1913, 1915 (Box-folder 47 / 12)
    - Statements of accounts, 1913-1921 (Box-folder 47 / 13)
    - Trial balances, 1915, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 47 / 14)
    - Miscellaneous (includes bills, vouchers, etc.), 1914-1919 (Box-folder 47 / 15)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreement with Wheaton Brothers re Halifax Ocean Terminals Railway, 1916 (Box-folder 47 / 16)
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation, minutes of one meeting, dissolution, 1912-1921 (Box-folder 47 / 17)
  - Subject Files
    - Azilda-Cartier and Levak contracts (Sudbury, Ont.; includes correspondence, financial records), 1913-1915 (Box-folder 47 / 18)
    - Bulwer Junction (Minn.) property (includes correspondence, maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 7], 1912, 1924 (Box-folder 47 / 19)
    - John C. Cox equipment, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 47 / 20)
    - Intercolonial Railway contract (Halifax, N.S.; includes correspondence, financial records), 1913-1915 (Box-folder 47 / 21)
    - Joliette and Lake Manuan Colonization Railway Company contract (includes correspondence, financial records), 1916 (Box-folder 47 / 22)
    - Montreal aquaduct contract (includes correspondence, court case, financial records, progress reports, and specifications), 1913-1919 (Box-folder 47 / 23-28)
    - Montreal power development (includes correspondence, financial records, legal documents, reports, clippings), 1911-1922 (Box-folder 48 / 1-4)
  - Miscellany
    - Blueprints: Bucyrus Company steamshovel, n.d. (Box-folder 48 / 5)
    - Steel reinforcement bars for retaining walls, 1916 (Box-folder 48 / 6)
    - Tuberculin tests on cows owned by company, 1918 (Box-folder 48 / 7)
    - Miscellaneous (includes notes, sand sample tests, application for industrial or commercial track), 1911-1913, n.d. (Box-folder 48 / 8)
- Cook Tunnel Company / New Gould Mining Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Owen Byrnes (also includes prospectus for Landers Valley Ranch), 1921-1928 (Box-folder 48 / 9)
    - J.N. Camden, 1922-1926 (Box-folder 48 / 10)
    - John P. Cowing, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 48 / 11)
    - R.J. Kinzer, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 48 / 12)
    - Edwin Lausier, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 48 / 13)
    - National Bank of Montana, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 48 / 14)
    - R.L. Northcutt (re organization of venture), 1922 (Box-folder 48 / 15)
    - Claude Siems, 1922-1927 (Box-folder 48 / 16)
    - C-W (correspondents include C.A. Crawford, Crystal Copper Company, Robert H. Hazlett, Ingersoll-Rand Company, Peter McVeigh, J.D. Watson), 1922-1924, n.d. (Box-folder 48 / 17)
  - Assay Reports
    - Certificates of assay, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 48 / 18)
  - Financial Records
    - Distribution of accounts, 1922-1924, 1928 (Box-folder 48 / 19)
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation, minutes of one meeting (New Gould Mining Company), stockholder list, 1925, 1928 (Box-folder 48 / 20)
  - Clippings
    - "Jay Gould Tunnel will be 4,500 feet in length", 1922 (Box-folder 48 / 21)
- Gloria Mining Company
  - General Correspondence
    - E.J.W. Donahue, 1917-1924 (Box-folder 49 / 1-3)
    - Telegrams, 1917-1924 (Box-folder 49 / 4)
  - Assay Reports
    - Analyses of iron and manganese ores, 1917-1919, n.d. (Box-folder 49 / 5)
  - Financial Records
    - Check register, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 49 / 6)
    - Daily labor and operating reports, 1918 (Box-folder 49 / 7)
    - Expenses, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 49 / 8)
    - Journal, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 49 / 9)
    - Ledger, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 49 / 10)
    - Miscellaneous (includes equipment lists, schedule of manganese ore prices, trial balance), 1916-1923 (Box-folder 49 / 11)
  - Legal Documents
    - Ore contracts, 1916-1925 (Box-folder 49 / 12)
  - Maps
    - Maps of Gloria mine property [oversize maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 7], n.d. (Box-folder 49 / 13)
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation; resolution, 1918 (Box-folder 49 / 14)
  - Reports
    - Reports on property by Ernest LeDuc, Franklin Merritt, Walter Harvey Weed, 1911, 1915 (Box-folder 49 / 15)
    - "Report on a magnetic survey...Crow Wing County, Minnesota"; "Annual report of Inspector of Mines for Crow Wing County, Minnesota", 1917-1918 (Box-folder 49 / 16)
- Lexington Mining Company
  - Assay Reports
    - Certificates of assay, 1922 (Box-folder 49 / 17)
  - Financial Records
    - Taxes: Lewis and Clark County, 1901-1903 (Box-folder 49 / 18)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstract of title; legal notice, 1905-1916 (Box-folder 49 / 19)
  - Maps
    - Lexington mine and other claims in Scratchgravel Mining District, Lewis and Clark County [oversize maps in OVERSIZE FOLDER 7], 1922 (Box-folder 49 / 20)
  - Organization
    - Stock certificates signed by E.F. Child and George B. Child), 1881-1885 (Box-folder 49 / 21)
- Mcconnell, Cook And Company / A.b. Cook Missoula Properties
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - A.B. Cook and F.W. McConnell, 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 1-2)
    - Telegrams, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 50 / 3)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Arkansaw Traveller Publishing Company, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 50 / 4)
    - A (correspondents include Thomas E. Adams, R.C. Alden and Company, John F. Allan, M.J.E. Allison, C.H. Anderson, Rebecca Archer, John J. Applebury, John A. Armstrong, S.C. Ashby), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 5)
    - Bullen Bridge Company (C.A. Bullen), 1891 (Box-folder 50 / 6)
    - Bunnell and Eno Investment Company, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 7)
    - B (correspondents include Baker and Brown Real Estate and Collections, C.W. Barber, H.P. Bartholomew, H.K. Beck, R.A. Bell, William S. Bell, D.C. Bennington, Walter M. Bickford, L.D. Bingham, Hiram S. Blanchard, Fielding Bradford, A.J. Bradley, Theodore Brantly, Brown and Haywood Stained Glass Works, Sidney H. Butler, T.H. Burke, A.H. Burns, W.C. Buskett, Butte Real Estate Chronicle), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 8-10)
    - R.L. Clinton; Clinton and Proctor, 1890 (Box-folder 50 / 11)
    - Tom Cox, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 50 / 12)
    - C (correspondents include D.W. Campbell; Thomas H. Carter; Casey, Holland and Company; M. Cassell; R.M. Cobban and Company; N.H. Connolly; J.R. Conrey; George Coscadden; W.C. Crandall), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 13-14)
    - Henry H. Davis, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 15)
    - D (correspondents include Dargen and James, R.A. Day, Leonie Demers, N.T. Dinsmore, W.H. Dittmer, James Downey, R.G. Dun and Company), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 16)
    - E (correspondents include E.D. Edgerton, Ehle and Dickinson, C.E. Ellis, John W. Eviss), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 17)
    - Finnegan Manufacturing Company, 1891 (Box-folder 50 / 18)
    - Fire Association of Philadelphia, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 19)
    - First National Bank of Missoula, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 50 / 20)
    - F (correspondents include E.J. Field, John T. Firth, Fleckstein and Mayer, Folk and Devine, Forbes and Davis, Charles H. Fuller), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 21)
    - W.G. Gooding, Commission Merchant (includes price quotes on mining properties), 1890 (Box-folder 50 / 22)
    - Guardian Assurance Company, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 23)
    - G (correspondents include F.P. Gable, George H. Garnett, W.C. Gass, C.M. Gates, John B. Gavin, F.M. Geer, M.P. Gilchrist, John D. Gill, E.C. Gove, N.N. Grant, A.J. Gray, F.R. Griffith), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 50 / 24)
    - Harry H. Hook, 1890 (Box-folder 50 / 25)
    - S.P. Hull, 1892 (Box-folder 50 / 26)
    - H (correspondents include John J. Hagerty, J.C. Hall, Luther Harrison, N.Y. Hass, W.W. Heacock, G.M. Hedderich, Arthur Helwig, T.J. Holt and Company, Hosum and Curtin, W.J. Hunter, Charles S. Hutchinson), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 1)
    - A.W. Ide, map publisher, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 51 / 2)
    - I (correspondents include Independent Publishing Company, Investors Directory Company, The Irrigation Age, Francis Irvine), 1890-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 3)
    - Jarvis-Conklin Mortgage Trust Company, 1889-1890 (Box-folder 51 / 4-5)
    - J (correspondents include G.W. Jackson, C.B. Jacquemin and Company, George R. Jenkins and Company, Journal Publishing Company), 1890-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 6)
    - R.W. Kay, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 7)
    - L. Kimball Printing Company, 1890 (Box-folder 51 / 8)
    - W. Klingberg, civil engineer, 1891 (Box-folder 51 / 9)
    - K (correspondents include Julius Kahn, P.H. Kelly, J.M. Kennedy, Clarence J. Kinna, Frank Kinne, Karl A. Knupfer, P.C. Krigbaum and Company), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 10)
    - L (correspondents include Leon A. LaCroix, S.G. Larimore, P. Larson, Phil E. Lawrence, N. Lester, J.B. Lewis, B.F. Liepner, Robert Love, R.A. Luke and Company), 1890-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 11)
    - McConnell and Clayberg (N.W. McConnell, O.W. McConnell), 1890 (Box-folder 51 / 12)
    - F.W. McConnell (after partnership dissolved), 1894-1895 (Box-folder 51 / 13)
    - J.R. McLaren (Bitter Root Land Agency), 1889-1891 (Box-folder 51 / 14)
    - John F. McLennon (Northwest Abstract Company), 1890 (Box-folder 51 / 15)
    - Mc (correspondents include N.J. McConnell, architect; D.F. McDevitt, architect; James D. McDermid; Ed H. McDonald; Edgar McKeen; J.C. McKie; D.M. McLeod; John McMurray), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 51 / 16)